Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Hello.
I come from outside the wall.
where we have all
but destroyed each other.
We designed your city
as an experiment.
We believe it is the only way to recover
the humanity we have lost.
And we created factions
to ensure peace.
But we believe there will be
those among you
who will transcend these factions.
These will be the Divergent.
They are the true purpose
of this experiment.
They are vital to humanity's survival.
If you're watching this now.
then at least one of you is proof
that our experiment has succeeded.
The time has come for you to emerge
from your isolation and rejoin us.
On Evelyn's orders.
this gate is now closed.
We've allowed you to believe
that you're the last of us.
But you're not.
Mankind waits for you.
with hope. beyond the wall.
We're almost there.
Yeah. I'm right behind you.
What. are you afraid of heights?
No. Who told you that?
Sometimes.
when I look past the wall.
I think that I can see
something out there.
- Do you?
- No. I don't.
Maybe you need to look harder.
I am looking.
I'm just not seeing what you're seeing.
When it's right
in front of your face. you will.
So we're really gonna do this?
Yeah.
People of Chicago...
I know you're curious
about what's beyond the wall.
but sometimes walls
are there to protect us.
Remember. the Founders were the ones
who divided us into factions.
So until we know their intentions.
the wall must stay closed.
Jeanine is dead.
Today. we begin the trials
of her conspirators...
Put the traitors on trial.
close down the gate.
Didn't take her long to make
the same mistakes as Jeanine.
I need to talk to her.
I still think
I can bring her around.
But that doesn't change
anything. right?
No.
I need you to get
some things for me.
Just this?
You're sure you don't want
the sun and moon as well?
- I know it's a lot.
- It's impossible.
- So?
- So I'll make it happen.
Well. hello. ladies.
Where we going? Can I come?
- Give it up. Peter.
- Oh. so hostile!
There's no factions.
We can be friends. right?
Can't we all just get along?
Tris.
You should be up there
with all the other leaders of the city.
No. that's not me.
I don't wanna make the rules.
Great leaders don't seek power.
They're called by necessity.
The people need you.
Look at me!
Look at me! You rat!
- Back up!
- You ready to die today?
That's right! Yeah!
Move!
Just sit tight.
String his ass up!
We all find ourselves
on new ground.
I dedicated my life
to seeking the truth.
But under Jeanine.
it passed me by.
And for that.
I humbly apologize.
But my personal failure
has only strengthened my resolve
to make things right.
While the faction of Candor
may no longer exist.
I want everyone to know that I will not
stop leading the pursuit of honesty
as we rebuild our city.
Yeah!
Let the trials begin!
Justice will be done!
Yeah!
Yeah.
May the truth set you free.
Now there is no doubt. Max. that you
helped Jeanine take over Chicago
and exert brutal control
over its citizens.
So my only question
to you is this...
Did you feel justified in murdering
people in support of her regime?
Absolutely.
People are sheep.
They need a shepherd
to guide them.
And when they resist.
they're slaughtered.
- Monster.
- We should slaughter you!
Kill him!
Yeah. kill him!
Kill him now!
- Kill him!
- Don't kill him!
- Let him live!
- Kill him!
- Kill him now!
Rise above it!
You can't do this!
Stop it!
Let him live!
We're better than this!
- Rise above it!
- No!
Jeanine...
Jeanine is dead.
Let's not keep her spirit alive.
- Kill him!
- Let him live!
What are you going to do?
They need an answer.
This is an execution.
No. This is a trial.
And I yield
to the wishes of the people.
It is time that we break
from the past.
Yeah!
Kill him!
He needs to die!
- He's a murderer!
- He should die!
I don't wanna die.
Neither did your sheep.
Whoo! Yeah!
There was a time I would've said.
"I leave you in love. not malice."
That time is past.
- Coward!
- Traitor!
Get out! Get out!
Traitor!
Get out. now! Get out!
Out. out. out. out!
Beatrice!
I'm sorry.
You incited a mob.
Good luck controlling them.
Beatrice. please!
Don't let them kill me!
Beatrice. no!
Beatrice!
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
We need to show a united front.
especially since Tris
refuses to stand with us.
- I'm not gonna tell Tris what to do.
- Well. you need to try.
Do you really think that you can
stop people leaving this city?
The wall's on total lockdown.
My soldiers have orders.
No one gets out.
Why did you go to war with Jeanine
if you were just gonna become her?
Leaders need to make tough decisions
to protect their people.
You'll understand that
when you take over for me.
I'm doing this for you.
You know. it might
not be the best time to leave.
I know. but we can't be here
for every fight.
And the message said to come out
and meet the rest of the world.
And we know absolutely nothing
about the people who sent it.
But aren't you curious
to find out?
What about our home?
I don't think our home
exists anymore.
Maybe the way to help Chicago
is going beyond the wall.
And what if there's nothing out there?
What if there is nothing left?
I can live with that
if you're with me.
But I can not live
without trying.
You know.
it's Caleb's trial tomorrow.
Yeah. I know.
I don't owe him anything.
No. No. you don't.
I'm gonna deal with this one.
Do you think I'm asking
your permission?
No. please. Four. No.
Four. Four. please.
don't kill me. I'm sorry.
Four. I'm sorry!
You tried to kill
your own sister. Caleb.
You brought this on yourself.
I'm sorry.
For everything.
Come on.
We're going up.
Come on. come on.
- Beatrice?
- Walk slowly.
Hey!
All Erudite prisoners are supposed
to be locked in the cages.
Stop!
I can handle this one myself.
Bring 'em in!
You can come out now. Caleb.
Thank you. Four.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
It was your sister's idea.
You saved me?
It's what you do for family.
Get in the car.
I knew it.
- Hey. partners.
- What are you doing. Peter?
Get out of here.
Yeah. that's what I'm doing.
I'm getting out of here.
Look. I don't wanna be here
when your crazy mom
goes around killing everybody
who used to work for Jeanine. okay?
Look. I can join you guys.
or I could... yell. "Help! Help!
Hey. they're getting away!"
- Peter. get in the car.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Get in the car.
- Thank you.
What's up. Caleb?
Yeah!
You want the truth?
He's dead! Yeah!
Justice for all!
You do have a plan. right?
I didn't hear anything
about a prisoner transfer.
Well. you're hearing it from me.
Let me see
your movement order.
I got it.
Right here.
I got everything.
just open the gate.
One more. come on.
one more! Yeah!
Edgar! Tobias Eaton
took Caleb Prior out of his cage.
Come on. let's go. now.
Come on.
let's do some more!
You a statue?
Open the gate.
Did they come through here?
Let's get out of here.
They're getting away.
Tobias Eaton is abetting
Caleb Prior's escape.
That makes him a traitor.
Shoot to kill.
Nobody goes over that wall.
We have our orders.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Not the same as reading it
in books. huh?
Okay. coast is clear.
It's time to see
what's out there.
Okay. On me.
Shit. Release now!
I got him.
I'm sorry. Four.
Come on. come on!
Christina!
I'm okay.
That part of the plan. stiff?
Evelyn
electrified the fence.
Ugh!
We did it.
Tori?
Tori!
Tori. Tori!
Tori! Oh. God. Tori?
Come on. We gotta go.
Come on.
No! Tori!
Tori...
Load up! Load up!
All right. let's go.
Come on. it's this way.
Holy shit.
What happened here?
Didn't exactly send out the welcoming
committee for you. stiff.
Shut up. Peter.
"Humanity
welcomes you with hope."
What humanity?
This hole looks radioactive.
Or at least it was
in the last 200 years.
Meaning what exactly?
Somebody seriously
messed up the world.
Shit.
Great.
Now the sky's bleeding.
This way.
Come on. let's go.
Now. come on.
This is fun.
I'm glad we did this.
What if there's
nothing else out there?
There has to be.
I'm scared.
Yeah. I think
that's a good thing.
You guys hear that?
- It's an engine.
- Someone's coming for us.
- It's Edgar! Go. go!
- Go!
All right.
Go. go! Cut back! Go!
Hollis!
No! Hollis!
What?
Whoa! What?
What is it?
Don't be afraid.
There's nothing to worry about.
You're safe now.
Welcome. Four.
Tris Prior. it's an honor
to meet you.
How do you know our names?
What the...
Uh-oh.
Welcome to the future.
We've been waiting for you.
Our plasma globes will protect you
from the toxicity.
Hey...
- We're gonna be okay.
- Yeah.
Look.
This is incredible.
This is insane!
Gadzooks!
It's Tris!
Welcome to the Bureau
of Genetic Welfare.
My name is Matthew.
Now. let's get you
into decontamination.
It's them
from Chicago.
It's her. Tris Prior.
She made it.
There's nothing
to worry about.
You're being decontaminated
from the toxins which plague our world.
Please remove your clothes and place
them in the incineration hatch.
Please step forward.
Place your feet on the mark.
You're clean. Please place your arm
into the tube in the wall.
There's nothing to worry about. Tris.
Please place your arm
into the tube.
I've never felt so clean in my life.
That was the best weird shower
I've ever had.
Little cold...
Hey. yours is different.
Why are they all different?
Hello and welcome
to the Bureau of Genetic Welfare.
In the early part of the 21st century.
scientists first discovered
a way to map.
then edit. the human genome.
Or you can choose health.
You can choose to settle
for merely adequate.
Or you can choose
excellent.
A genetic solution puts you
in control of your life.
So why just hope
for a better future
when you can choose
perfection?
Choose Perfexia.
But what started as an attempt
to erase humanity's faults
almost erased humanity itself
Genetic modification deepened
the rifts between people.
and as they got more entrenched.
the world began to tear apart.
until humanity crossed a line
from which it could never return.
In the ashes of civilization.
a small group of genetically
unmodified individuals
established the Bureau
of Genetic Welfare here.
at Chicago's O 'Hare Airport.
Our mission is to oversee
a grand experiment
to purify the human genome.
That experiment
is the city of Chicago.
Your participation
in the Bureau's work
means you are now
the guardians of the future.
Your destiny begins today.
Now. please follow me.
What's an airport?
Life in the Bureau can be demanding.
but the work is worth every sacrifice.
It's them!
We don't have all the resources
we would like. of course.
but I think you'll find your
accommodations more than adequate.
- Whoa!
- They're in person here!
- Who are they?
- We bring them in from the Fringe.
get them healthy.
give them a second chance.
Hi. Four.
- Hi. Four.
- Hey.
How do they know
who we are?
The experiment is the entire focus
of the Bureau.
Our surveillance technology
is centuries ahead of anything
you've known in Chicago.
They've grown up
watching you.
Nothing creepy about that.
You have to forgive
everyone for staring.
but your arrival is the most exciting
event some of us have ever known.
Welcome to your new home.
Where's Four?
Did you hurt him?
I told you I wanted them unharmed.
He went with them.
Willingly.
But he's alive?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
He betrayed you.
No. It's just love.
He's your son.
He should be loyal. I'm loyal.
Yes. you are. So rest up.
I need you ready to fight.
What do you think?
I think they've been studying us
for 200 years and we need to catch up.
We're gonna give it
a chance. right?
Yeah.
'Course we are.
I wish we were alone.
Excuse me.
The director's
ready to see you.
Yeah. er. sorry.
I meant Tris. alone.
We can't go together?
Since you were the one who opened
the box which invited you here.
the director would like
to thank you personally.
I'll see you later.
- Clothes.
- Thanks.
This way.
Go ahead. Put your wrist
under the scanner.
Access granted.
Pure.
Just never imagined the world
to be this big.
Ah. Chicago is just one
of 50 major cities
that used to exist
on th is continent alone.
Beyond that is oceans and more land
than you can imagine.
It's all like this now?
Yeah.
All except for Providence.
Which is why what we're doing here
is so important. Tris.
Hello.
You must be the director.
Oh. please.
call me David.
It is a pleasure
to finally meet you.
You must have
so many questions.
I'm a bit overwhelmed.
I'm still processing it all.
Oh. Tris. I know you.
I watched you being born.
I saw the love that your mother
and father had for you.
I watched a little girl
have a happy childhood
and grow into a courageous young woman
capable of making choices.
Dauntless. Defying Jeanine.
Saving Chicago.
To your people.
you are Divergent.
To the Council.
you are a freak.
To me. you are a miracle.
David. are you aware of what's happening
in Chicago right now?
Of course. Yes.
The people at Erudite
really made a mess of things.
but I don't want you
to worry about that.
Restoring order in Chicago
is as important to me as it is to you.
It's the only way
to save the Damaged.
What is the Damaged?
The genetic alterations
had disastrous consequences.
Too brave.
and you're cruel.
Too peaceful.
and you're passive.
Too smart.
and you lose compassion.
Like your brother.
Caleb's Damaged?
Yes.
For nearly 200 years.
the greatest scientific minds
have lived here to test a theory.
If we could rescue
genetically damaged people
from the toxic environment
in the Fringe
and put them in a safe place.
like Chicago.
then perhaps. over time.
man's genetic material
would heal itself.
return to its original form.
And I'm one of those people.
You are the only one.
That doesn't make any sense.
I mean. uh. Four is Divergent.
There's lots of Divergents.
Not Divergent. Tris. Pure.
You are genetically Pure.
The rest are still Damaged.
- Four?
- Damaged.
Not as much as Caleb.
but Damaged.
If we can understand
what made you.
maybe we can use that knowledge
to help the Damaged.
But what does this
have to do with Chicago?
I answer to the Council.
They're the ones who ultimately
determine our fate. yours and mine.
I'm gonna bring you with me
to Providence to meet them.
When they see
that it's possible.
that you were possible.
it will change everything.
I understand it's hard
to take my word for it.
But if you don't believe me.
believe your mother.
My mother?
Your mother Natalie
wasn't born in Chicago.
She was born in the Fringe
and rescued by the Bureau.
No. that's impossible.
See for yourself.
What are those?
They're your mother's
memory tabs.
With them. you can watch
the world th rough her eyes.
What do I do?
Place one on each temple.
Natalie! Come on!
I'm not Natalie.
We need to hide!
Come on!
They're coming! Run!
The Fringers!
Run!
I'm not Natalie.
Natalie. no!
No!
Bureau soldiers!
Left! Flank left!
Hit right. hit right.
hit right!
We're taking you
to the Bureau.
You're safe.
You don't have to be
afraid anymore.
How many more
did you save today?
Not enough.
We never get enough.
Chicago has got to work. David.
It's the only hope for us.
In the ashes
of civilization.
a small group of genetically
unmodified individuals
established the Bureau
of Genetic Welfare here.
at Chicago's O 'Hare Airport.
You're safe.
...grand experiment to purify
the human genome.
You're safe now.
Your destiny
begins today.
Tris. in a moment of need.
your mother did something
that no one had done before.
She volunteered to leave
the safety of the Bureau
to enter the experiment herself.
She did this because she knew
the Damaged were worth saving.
She believed in the experiment so much.
she was willing to be a part of it.
If I can show the Council
your miracle can be replicated...
...then her life's work is complete.
The Council will be forced
to look at every human being.
no matter where they were born.
as worthy of life.
Help me.
You saved a city.
Help me save the world.
It was amazing.
It was like I was her
and seeing it all through her eyes.
Hmm...
I still can't believe
my mom is from this place.
Well. I can see why she left.
Do you trust him?
David?
I trust her.
Yeah.
- Access denied.
- Tris.
Access granted.
There you are.
You ready?
Say hi to David for me.
Tobias Eaton.
You've been assigned to me.
I'm Nita. Let's go.
Why isn't everyone allowed upstairs?
That would be
one of the Council's many rules.
Certainly not mine.
This separation.
I don't like it.
I agree. And in time.
that won't be necessary.
But. Tris. I don't know who told you
that being different was a bad thing.
Because I know
it wasn't your mother.
Oh. I know I can replicate this.
All I need is time.
Look. Regina.
let's talk.
You seem like a nice lady. but I'm
really not a desk job kind of guy.
I get claustrophobic.
I need to be where the action is.
The job of surveillance is to keep tabs
on the devolving situation in Chicago.
This is where the action is.
Hayes. this will be your pod.
Prior. you're next door.
Resistance is growing.
Evelyn is beginning to respond.
Watch what's happening.
File a report.
Wait. what? Hold on.
I just escaped from Chicago.
Now you're saying I gotta sit here
and watch it for the rest of my life?
With Caleb?
Perhaps you'd prefer
to be banished to the Fringe?
Wow. this surveillance
technology's incredible.
Whoever created this
is a genius.
Well. thank you.
It was a labor of love.
Ass kisser.
Keep it up. Prior.
And you. get to it.
Ah!
That's an awful lot of firepower.
The Fringe is full
of dangerous people.
Put this on.
- What are these?
- Personal drones.
Expands your field of vision and
provides 3-D modeling of environ ments.
Just like old times
at Dauntless. huh?
Except there's nothing old
about any of this.
Here.
Thanks.
Activate the headgear.
The left hand
activates the drones.
Does it do anything else?
Not much.
Use the drones
to find the targets.
It'll take you a while
to get the hang of it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Identified.
Target identified.
I think I got the hang of it.
Hmm.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah. Of course.
If my mother was born
in the Fringe.
then how did she end up
in Chicago?
I mean. you couldn't just send her
through the gate. right?
No. No. the Council's
always careful
how they introduce any new element
to the experiment.
Right. But when they need to.
they intervene.
Yes.
So why aren't they intervening now?
Well. they will.
We just have to make our case.
Can I still count on you to help me?
Yes.
Can I count on you?
Jeanine never had
a chance against you.
The sooner we get finished.
the sooner we leave for Providence.
The Allegiant? That's what
you're calling yourselves?
Amity just doesn't seem
appropriate anymore.
So what exactly
are you allegiant to?
The faction system?
The factions kept Chicago
peaceful for a long time.
Well. I wouldn't know about that
because I was forced out of my faction.
I gave up my life.
my child. everything.
I understand your anger.
Evelyn. I do.
But the way forward...
The way forward
has already begun.
I know I said I'd be alone.
but I'm not Candor.
And I'm not Amity.
So I will lie and I will fight
if I have to.
You see these scars?
I wasn't born Amity.
And I can assure you. I'm not afraid
to fight for what I believe in.
Seems like we're two peas in a pod.
But it doesn't have
to be this way.
We can come to some
sort of agreement.
- Get back!
- Stop! Stop!
- No. no!
- Get outta here!
All right. Caleb.
Keep me posted
if anything changes. all right?
- Hey.
Caleb said that some of the Dauntless
are lining up with Johanna.
But the rest of Candor
is still solidly with Evelyn.
Things are spiraling
out of control.
Has David said anything
about what he can do?
Well. yeah. once we talk to the Council.
then the Bureau can step in.
So it all hinges on the mysterious
Council. does it?
- What if they say no?
- David is confident that they won't.
David. Right.
You know I found out
why I can't go upstairs?
I'm Damaged
and you're Pure.
I know.
You know. When were
you gonna tell me?
I don't know. I... I guess
I didn't think that it mattered.
Why doesn't it matter?
Because it doesn't make a difference
if you're Pure or if you're Damaged.
You're still the same person to me.
Look. I know that it's not perfect
by any means.
but the Bureau saved my mother
from the Fringe.
I wouldn't be here without them.
What do you actually know
about what they do in the Fringe?
You know
what they tell you.
- Yeah. but...
- I'm sorry.
He needs you upstairs.
The people are nice.
Weird. but nice.
Yeah. they're definitely
weird. That's for sure.
You kinda get used to it.
- Yeah.
Next time you go to the Fringe.
I want in.
- You're not ready.
- I'm going.
Tris. I am more than aware
that the separation has been difficult
for you and Four.
But I've watched you both
enough to know
that I think the two of you
are going to work it out.
We're fine.
Everything's fine.
Good. Let's get to work.
Here we go!
Fall in. people! Weather's clear.
we are green for a run.
- Let's go!
- You. let's go. let's go!
- Move! Let's go!
- Ready to go!
Let's go.
All right. here's the deal.
listen up!
This may be
a humanitarian mission.
but the Lindale Settlement
is very dangerous.
- Everybody clear?
- Yes!
- So what is the lifespan out here?
- 25. 30 years.
If we get people early. they can live
up to 50 or 60 in the Bureau.
Dauntless. if it was up to me.
you would not be out here.
I know you think it was tough
in Chicago. but this is the Fringe.
- Understood?
- Yes.
Mission is to save
as many kids as possible.
They've grown up
in hellish conditions.
But you have your weapons handy.
You stick to protocol.
I don't wanna lose anyone.
Bullfrogs! Go!
We're under! Go!
Go. go. go!
We gotta move!
Drones!
Go!
- Help!
- Stop. stop. stop!
Hey. hey. hey!
Everything's okay.
Put me down!
Please! No!
No! No!
Everything's gonna be
okay. Just follow me.
Uh...
Come on!
Run!
Searching target.
This way.
Target identified.
Go!
Stop!
- Stay away from us!
- Calm down. We're here to help.
- We don't need your help.
- I just wanna talk to you.
- Not gonna lose my family.
- Hey!
- Whoa. whoa. whoa! Stop!
- Don't!
Get off him!
Hey. get off my kid!
Don't touch him!
What did you do?
- It's okay. it's all right.
- I wanna see my dad.
Four. let's go!
Gotta move!
It's all right. it's okay.
Go! We gotta move.
we gotta move.
Let's go. come on.
come on!
- Romit!
- Don't.
What the hell
is going on here?
Just do your job. Dauntless.
Let's go.
Move!
Said. "Let's go!"
One man. two children.
down on the bridge! Go!
- We're here to help you!
- Go!
- Eyes down!
- Shut up! Look at me!
Hey. you. stop!
It's called soap.
You should try it.
What's up. stiff?
You lost?
I wanted to see Four. David and I
are leaving for Providence.
On a first name basis
with the director. huh?
- You work fast.
- Peter. can you leave her alone?
I don't need you to defend me.
Attention!
Get us ready for Providence.
We're on my ship within an hour.
- Yes. sir.
- Follow me.
David. hey. I was wondering
if I could talk to you about my job.
You know. 'cause I'm not
really a typist and...
Or if you're busy today. I get it.
totally fine. We'll talk tomorrow.
Good idea.
I need to talk to you.
What is this. Nita?
- Vaccinations.
- What do you mean. vaccinations?
We weren't given vaccinations.
Four.
Look at this.
Hey. what's your name?
My name?
Hey.
I'm sorry about your dad.
My dad?
- All right. I'll see you back at base.
- Yep.
This is not
a humanitarian mission.
We're not saving kids.
We're stealing them.
This is what we do.
Now you know.
David takes them out from here.
wipes their memories with the gas.
and raises them in the Bureau.
If you take away what they know.
then you take away who they are.
Yeah. I think that's the point.
They were all unarmed.
I won't surrender to this.
Round up everyone who's left.
We take the fight to Evelyn.
Yeah. I'm loading up.
We're moving.
Today we take Evelyn down.
Whatever it takes.
Yeah!
This is all real time.
I mean. the surveillance technology
they have in place is extraordinary.
Caleb. can you get out of your head
for a second?
This is our home.
And there's gonna be a war.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna do something about it.
Four! What are you trying to do?
Access denied.
I'm getting Tris.
We're leaving.
You can't go up there.
- What do you think you're doing?
- Four.
- You cannot be in here.
- It's not gonna work.
- Pure.
Central elevator's
been compromised.
- Hey. What?
- We're leaving. Right now.
What? I can't.
Look. you don't understand yet.
but these people have been lying to you.
Lying? What are you
talking about?
Look. whatever they've told you.
they have been...
Put the guns down.
He has been stealing
children from their families.
- We're giving them a better life.
- By killing their parents?
It was an unfortunate accident. sir.
One terrible accident doesn't mean
it was the wrong thing to do.
Tris. this is not the place
that we thought it was.
If you had enough to save one person.
and your choice was between
a healthy child or a sick old man.
- who would you choose?
- I wouldn't choose.
Good. Now they're both dead.
We have to go.
Tris. we're going back to Chicago.
We should never have left.
- No. we have to wait.
- No. we've been waiting. okay?
David is not the person
that you think he is.
Four. you know nothing about David.
You've no idea
what we've been working on up here.
What have you been working on?
Do you have any idea
what is going on out there?
Yes. of course I do.
Why do you think we're going to meet
with the Council?
Tris...
I want you to listen to me.
Tris.
You're coming with me.
I have to go.
You're making a mistake.
You ready?
Yeah.
Autopilot engaged.
If you wanna go back to Chicago.
I'll take you.
No. thanks.
You're gonna walk
across the Fringe? I don't think so.
There's no rule saying
you can't go home. Four. Come on.
- Yeah.
- I'll come with you.
All set!
Take us to Chicago.
Look. I understand how you're feeling.
but what you're about to do
has ramifications for people
all over the world.
If Four doesn't see that.
it's not your fault.
David never wanted you to see
what you saw out on the Fringe.
He keeps tight control.
Nothing happens
without his approval.
And his ship is the only one
that can fly through the camo wall.
Why are you telling me this?
We're not taking you to Chicago.
Hold on!
Welcome to Providence.
I see why they don't want to share.
Someday the whole world's
gonna look this beautiful.
So. as you can see.
there are multiple genetic markers
supporting this conclusion.
Standard personality tests.
Behavioral evaluations.
Stimulus response.
She's passed them all
with flying colors.
It all sounds great.
assuming it's the truth.
- Phillip...
- David has lied to us before.
Haven't you. David?
I'd like to hear from the girl.
Well. I don't know why.
She can't tell you anything I'm not.
Indulge us. David.
This must all come as quite
a shock to you. Miss Prior.
finding out that you're Pure.
Um...
"Pure." I'm not even sure
what that's supposed to mean.
But. yes. it is
shocking to me.
Shocking that the more
I learn about the past.
the more I feel like you're all making
the same mistakes over and over again.
Tris. this is not the way.
Let her speak. David.
What mistakes. Tris?
Human beings can not
be categorized in this way.
It doesn't work.
Maybe it's time to start
embracing everyone
instead of dividing them
into groups.
regardless of whether they're
Pure or they're Damaged.
That isn't
what we're here to discuss.
Well. it should be!
Look. I know that all of this
is just an experiment to you.
but these people in Chicago are real.
And they are in a war right now
because of divisions that you created
and you are doing
nothing to help them.
David has control over
the administration of Chicago.
He's only here to extend his funding.
Which we would be
happy to do.
but if things are
as bad as she says. David.
shouldn't you get
your house in order first?
You said that you couldn't do anything.
I am doing something.
I'm bringing back the factions.
What? Why?
I hoped the Allegiant would take care
of the problem for me.
The factions work. Tris.
They keep the peace.
They created you.
I never should've trusted you.
You want change with no sacrifice.
You want peace with no struggle.
The world doesn't work like that.
You okay?
I'll be fine.
The Bureau isn't far.
I need to get to Chicago.
Tell Evelyn she's got
a lot bigger problems than Johanna.
Yeah.
You'll need this
to get through the camo wall.
We need your help. Tobias.
You don't know
what he's capable of.
What about Tris?
As long as she stays
in the Bureau. she's safe.
She's too valuable to him.
I'll need a head start.
So when David asks.
I want you to tell him
that I left you behind. Okay?
Why?
Because then Tris
will know you're lying.
There was an accident.
There was turbulence.
Not more than any other storm. but...
Lightning. maybe.
- We just went down.
- Where's Four?
I don't know.
I passed out.
When I came to. everyone was dead.
Four left me behind.
Okay. we search the settlements.
search the Fringe.
Make sure he's not there.
Don't worry. we'll find him.
I promise.
Four would never leave anyone
behind at the crash site.
Yeah. He told me
you would say that.
Four's trying to make
his way back to Chicago.
Peter.
Hello. David.
I didn't think that you knew my name.
I know all of the important people
from Chicago.
Really?
Well. if I'm so important.
then why did you give me
such a terrible job?
We all
have to make sacrifices.
I don't see you making any.
Peter...
I need help with something in Chicago.
What's in it for me?
Well. if you do well.
you can have any job you want.
Except mine.
Do you know where Peter is?
- Um... He's not in his pod?
- No.
No. I don't know where he is.
Is-is there something
that I can help you with?
Can you find Four?
You can't tell anyone.
Okay. of course.
Anything you need.
Beatrice.
Come on. Four. where are you?
Evelyn.
We found him outside the wall.
Take it off.
Where's my son?
I don't know.
Edgar told me what's out there.
so you better start talking
or we'll be holding your trial now.
No. you won't.
Because I have
something that you need.
Really?
And what's that?
The way to win your war.
- Hey.
Any news?
No.
- I'm sorry.
- Tris...
- Did you find him?
- Yes. I found Four.
And there's something else
you're gonna wanna see. too.
Okay. go.
Over there!
That's him! We got him!
Four.
Don't worry. he's fine.
Just keep watching.
What is this place?
You're gonna love it.
What is it?
Try it out. You'll see.
Just don't try it
on anyone you like.
I was wondering when you'd have
the courage to face me.
Three weeks
you leave me here.
I ran a faction!
I protected our son
from Jeanine's thugs.
Protected him?
Is that what you call it?
Beating your own child!
It made him who he is.
Make sure
he gets a good dose.
Tobias... I'm just trying
to help you to be better.
I'm s... I'm s... I'm sorry. but...
Who are you?
Huh...
Just imagine if you released
this on the Allegiant.
Not even Johanna will remember a time
that you weren't in charge.
Who exactly told you about this?
You have a very powerful friend
on the outside
if you choose to engage
instead of prepare.
- Does this friend have a name?
- David.
- David?
- You can tell my friend
I'm not gonna use that thing
unless it's a last resort.
Why would David support Evelyn?
Doesn't make any sense.
Are you okay?
I was worried about you.
Evelyn. you need to make peace
with the Allegiant.
No. Johanna made her choice.
I never wanted this war.
but I will end it. I promise you.
You have no idea what you're up against.
Johanna is not the issue.
Look. I know you're angry at me
and I understand that.
I'm just... I never meant...
This is hard for me. too.
I don't wanna have to keep you in here.
Then let me out.
I can't. I have responsibilities.
One day you'll understand that.
but right now I need you to stay here.
I'm gonna finish this.
One way or another.
How are you gonna finish this?
Hey. don't worry.
You won't have to be here for long.
What... What are you
talking about?
Well. Evelyn's deciding now.
If she uses the memory serum.
Chicago might forget its own name.
We have to go.
Get Christina and meet me outside.
Where are we going?
Home.
Access granted.
How's it going in Chicago?
Making sure it's safe from Evelyn
and the Factionless?
Tris. you need to forget about Chicago.
You know.
it's really funny. David.
You've been watching me for years
and you don't know anything about me.
You're wiping the memories
of everyone in Chicago. aren't you?
All right. uh. no...
You were never supporting
the Allegiant.
These people treated you terribly.
They killed your parents!
Four is there!
Four. Yes. yes. Four is there.
But he's Damaged.
just like the rest of them.
Where are you going?
I'm taking your ship
and I'm not coming back.
You can't fly.
Watch me.
Autopilot engaged.
Tris Prior is stealing my craft.
Bring her back.
Hurry.
Christina.
- These are for you and Tris.
- How'd you know we were leaving?
You're not the only ones
who hate David.
- Okay. come on.
- Thank you.
- Hold it!
- Get in. get in.
Hands to yourself
or I throw you out.
Let's go rescue Four.
Looks like three ships
are following us.
- Plasma craft engaged.
- Surround it.
Give her a nudge
towards the ground.
The autopilot
will bring her down safely.
Whoa!
What are they
trying to do?
They're trying to bring us
in for a landing.
I'm going manual.
Tris!
Pull up! Pull up!
Trying. I'm trying!
Altitude.
I got it.
Your orders. sir?
Shoot her down.
Before she reaches
the camo wall.
You can't follow her through.
We're dead.
We're gonna die. we're gonna die.
we're gonna die!
Hold on!
It's gonna be close.
There has to be a way
to shut off the gas.
Look at the ventilation system.
It's all over the city.
Down there.
Johanna.
We got here just in time.
It's time. Evelyn.
You said the gas was a last resort.
Well...
How do you think
your trial is going to end?
Let me know the second
the serum is released.
You got it. Good luck.
Thank you.
How do these drones work?
Turn your headgear on.
And?
Watch and learn.
Stop right there!
Drop your weapons!
Hey. Hey. whoa.
what are you doing?
Put me down!
All right.
this one's all you.
- Easy!
- Sorry.
Stay where you are!
That's my girl.
Recon!
Screw this!
I'm outta here.
What the hell is that?
Hey.
Hey... I'm sorry.
I never should have trusted him.
You were doing what
you thought was right.
I love you.
We should find Evelyn.
Come on.
Serum status: ready.
Now. if you press
that button...
We're completely safe
inside the vault.
And no one else will ever know
what happened to them.
Your choice.
Initialize
serum vaporization.
Guys!
Guys! They just
initiated the serum.
Did you find a way
to shut it off?
Come on.
Not yet.
This way.
It's locked.
I'll see if I can get in
from the control room.
Evelyn. you have to stop this
right now.
I...
I didn't wanna do this.
but I have to.
I'm the only one who knows
how to save Chicago.
I was right to close the gate.
but no one listened. No one!
Not even you.
The Allegiant brought this
on themselves.
Evelyn. that serum is not just gonna
wipe the memories of the Allegiant.
It's gonna do it to the whole city.
What?
Whatever they told you
was a lie.
Oh. God...
- Oh. God.
- Evelyn...
I wanna stand by your side.
But what you do to the city.
you do to me.
Mom...
Tobias...
I won't know who you are.
Don't do it.
Please.
Go.
No!
That's why you pick a guy like me
for a job like this.
I hope you're watching. David!
♪ Ba! ♪
Christina. have you
figured out the door yet?
Once it's locked from the inside.
the door won't open.
Well. keep trying.
Begin serum release.
Don't breathe it in!
Don't breathe in the gas!
Caleb. we're running
out of options here!
Hold on.
I think
I found something.
There's a choke point where the vapor
gets pumped out.
Cut their com line to the ship.
Caleb? Caleb!
Tris? Tris.
can you hear me?
Caleb!
I'm going in.
What? Huh?
Oh. shit!
What the...
- Make it stop!
- It's locked!
- Open the door!
Peter. open the door!
I will find you. Peter.
Tobias.
You're okay.
Oh. shit!
- Can you stop it?
- No.
Caleb. do you hear me?
Caleb. where are you?
Caleb Prior!
Sorry.
Tris. look at this. it's really smart.
So they ran the piping
through the air ducts.
Caleb. focus.
Just tell me where it is.
It's right here. There's an isolation
valve that controls the flow of the air.
But I don't know
how you're gonna get down there.
I do. Four!
Go.
Tris.
it's at the end of the hall.
Close the door.
Tris? I control everything.
I can even seal the room
you're in right now.
Just stop fighting.
There's another way.
Down the stairs.
This is foolish.
Just stop.
I made you.
You might as well be my child.
which is what
you're acting like.
A spoiled child.
Tris. at the end of the hall.
there's another way up the ladder.
It's over. Tris.
Searching target.
Target identified.
There you are.
You're right. David.
It is over.
No!
Serum release halted.
How's that for Damaged?
Clear.
It's clear.
We did it.
It's what you do for family.
Caleb. there's one more thing
I want you to do.
I wanna send
a message to David.
My name is Tris Prior.
And I'm here to reveal the truth.
There are others
who exist on this planet.
They do not view us as equals.
They call themselves the Pure
and they call us the Damaged.
They created a wall
to divide us from their world
and factions to divide us
from each other.
Hello? Come on!
You think you can ditch me like this?
Get me to do your dirty work
and then just wipe me away
like the rest of 'em?
We had a deal. pal!
We were their experiment
and it almost destroyed us.
I set the autopilot right
for our friend's neighborhood.
Along with a little surprise for when
it goes through the camouflage wall.
They tried to make us forget
who we are and where we 're from.
but they did not succeed.
So here we stand.
Together.
Not as five factions.
but as one city.
And we're gonna tear down their wall.
I want the penthouse!
Yeah! That's right!
Or a room in that really cool
upstairs area.
Okay. look...
I'll even take my old bunk back.
Just come on
and open the damn door!
Please!
You've seen us.
And now. we see you.
To those of you beyond the wall.
hear me loud and clear.
because I know you're listening.
Chicago is not your experiment.
It is our home.
And it always will be.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today